<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Camille Laville</title>
    <link>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Camille Laville</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Camille Laville</title>
      <link>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal conflicts and shocks: A narrative meta-analysis</title>
      <link>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/publication/academic-publications/2024-01-01_internal_conflicts_a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/publication/academic-publications/2024-01-01_internal_conflicts_a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Political Economy of Military Aircraft, the Case of Europe</title>
      <link>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/publication/academic-publications/2024-01-01_the_political_econom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/publication/academic-publications/2024-01-01_the_political_econom/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replication material &#34;Internal Conflicts and Shocks. A Narrative Meta-Analysis&#34;</title>
      <link>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/project/2023-02-07-mra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/project/2023-02-07-mra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Citation:  Laville, C., &amp;amp; Mandon, P. (2024). Internal conflicts and shocks: A narrative meta-analysis. Journal of Peace Research, 0(0). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/00223433241283323&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/00223433241283323&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can access the replication material by following the &amp;ldquo;Code&amp;rdquo; URL and selecting &amp;ldquo;View Raw&amp;rdquo; to download the ZIP file.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building forward better: a pathway to climate-resilient development in fragile and conflict-affected situations</title>
      <link>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/publication/academic-publications/2023-01-01_building_forward_bet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/publication/academic-publications/2023-01-01_building_forward_bet/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Off the Grass: Grassland Scarcity and the Security Implications of Cross-Border Transhumance Between Niger and Nigeria</title>
      <link>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/project/keep-off-the-grass-grassland-scarcity-and-the-security-implications-of-cross-border-transhumance-between-niger-and-nigeria/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/project/keep-off-the-grass-grassland-scarcity-and-the-security-implications-of-cross-border-transhumance-between-niger-and-nigeria/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2018, 1,300 people were killed and 300,000 displaced as a result of herder-farmer conflicts in Nigeria. These tensions threaten the already weakened security, economic development and food security in Western Africa. Indeed, cross-border transhumance of herders during the dry season is an important economic activity recognized by the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS). This practice is also an important adaptation strategy to climate change for Sahelian States that have developed a comparative advantage in producing and exporting livestock. However, the establishment of a harmonized legal framework surrounding this practice is hampered by coordination failures between Coastal States (primary receivers of livestock flows) and the Sahelian States (primary providers of livestock flows). The growth of the Nigerian agricultural sector through the expansion of agricultural land threatens the last open pastures and transhumance corridors. Indeed, Nigeria faces a scarcity of arable land for a growing rural population. Is competition for the remaining Nigerian grassland a factor of violence between nomadic herders from Niger and Nigerian farmers? Recent empirical evidence suggests that climate-induced migration of herders to nearby agricultural areas (short transhumance) is associated with a higher risk of herder-farmer conflict for the remaining pastoral resources. However, no analysis has been made on the case of lengthy and costly transhumance. This article analyses the security implications of cross-border transhumance between Niger and Nigeria at the scale of 0.5x0.5 degree cells between 2006 and 2016. Using spatial panel techniques and satellite data on land cover, it questions the importance of grassland grabbing strategies as a cause of the recent herder-farmer conflicts in Nigeria. The obtained results hardly coincide with the idea that transhumant herders from Niger enter into conflict with Nigerian farmers over the grabbing of the last grazing resources. Ultimately, the economy of Sahelian countries, which depends on livestock trade, is threatened by a political instrumentalization of herder-farmer conflicts through the rhetoric of &amp;ldquo;invaders against farmers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religious Authorities, Peace, and Political Conflict: Assessing the Impacts of Pope John Paul II&#39;s International Travels</title>
      <link>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/project/religious-authorities-peace-and-political-conflict-assessing-the-impacts-of-pope-john-paul-ii-s-international-travels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/project/religious-authorities-peace-and-political-conflict-assessing-the-impacts-of-pope-john-paul-ii-s-international-travels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Between 1978 and 2005, Pope John Paul II traveled to 102 developing countries with the aim, inter alia, of promoting interreligious peace to populations and policy makers. Despite an increasing involvement of religious leaders in peace-building activities, concerns rise on the propensity of religious issues to be locally exploited for political interests. This article examines the dynamic effects of John Paul II travels on the risk of political conflict in host countries depending on their religious demography. Our empirical strategy combines the development of a political conflict risk index, an impact assessment methodology, and the estimation of local projections. Our results show that the travels of John Paul II reduce the risk of conflict in host countries over a 4-year horizon, particularly when the proportion of Catholics is low. We also observe a temporary rise in the risk of conflict for religiously polarized countries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerability of Rural Households and Insecurity in West Africa</title>
      <link>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/publication/academic-publications/2020-01-01_vulnerability_of_rur/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/publication/academic-publications/2020-01-01_vulnerability_of_rur/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Causes of Civil Conflicts: Recent Advances Using Disaggregated Data</title>
      <link>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/publication/academic-publications/2019-01-01_the_causes_of_civil_/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/publication/academic-publications/2019-01-01_the_causes_of_civil_/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to analyze the socio-political risk? A key component of country risk</title>
      <link>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/publication/academic-publications/2018-01-01_how_to_analyze_the_s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/publication/academic-publications/2018-01-01_how_to_analyze_the_s/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allier securite et developpement, plaidoyer pour le Sahel</title>
      <link>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/publication/academic-publications/2016-01-01_allier_securite_et_d/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/publication/academic-publications/2016-01-01_allier_securite_et_d/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lavillecamille.netlify.app/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
